<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Md. Jehadul Karim (Sabit)</title>
    <link>https://zarif98sjs.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Md. Jehadul Karim (Sabit)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 20:48:39 +0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://zarif98sjs.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>AKash</title>
      <link>https://zarif98sjs.github.io/projects/akash/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 22:53:26 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zarif98sjs.github.io/projects/akash/</guid>
      <description>AKash is a simple Banking Application using Java &amp;amp; JavaFX
  Dependencies  JDK 11+ JAVAFX for Java 9+  How to run?  In the release folder, you&amp;rsquo;ll find Jar Files Edit the script files (.bat for windows/.sh for linux) according to your settings Execute the script files (First Server, then Client)  How to use   You can use command line of Server to execute ADMIN works</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Messenger</title>
      <link>https://zarif98sjs.github.io/projects/messenger/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 22:17:04 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zarif98sjs.github.io/projects/messenger/</guid>
      <description>A Simple Multi-Client Messenger with Java Socket Networking&amp;hellip; [ Java Executable Link Given Below ]
  Just like any other messenger, It has
 Sign Up and Log in
Sorting User Depending on Recent Activity
Unread Message Batch
Real time message update (with Customizable Frequency 1Hz)
Black Theme :3
 Screenshots  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Infinite Runner 2D</title>
      <link>https://zarif98sjs.github.io/projects/infinite-runner-2d/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 12:00:09 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zarif98sjs.github.io/projects/infinite-runner-2d/</guid>
      <description>Infinite Runner 2D is a 2D game using C Programming Language and iGraphics - An OpenGL Wrapper.
The game is about a boy keeps running and running, in his way he faces two types of obsacles. He needs to jump to avoid collisin. He can throw a Kunai to destroy one kind of object. But this throwing comes at a cost, 100 point is deducted each time it is thrown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://zarif98sjs.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 20:48:39 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zarif98sjs.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>About Me Hi, my name is Md. Jehadul Karim (Sabit). I’m from Dhaka, Bangladesh.
I’m an undergraduate student majoring in Computer Science &amp;amp; Engineering at BUET. I started my undergraduate life in April, 2019.
I am interested in Game Deveopment, Mobile Application Development &amp;amp; Software Development. I have created some Softwares with my current knowledge. You can find my works here.
In my spare time, I like to play Video Games, watching Movies and TV Series.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaFX Environment Setup</title>
      <link>https://zarif98sjs.github.io/posts/javafx-environment-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 20:32:14 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zarif98sjs.github.io/posts/javafx-environment-setup/</guid>
      <description>JavaFX Download JavaFX for 11, not for IntelliJ Bundled JDK
Windows and Linux Versions are different, one should not work on another.
Unzip JavaFX to your HDD
Go to Structure for New Projects
Add JavaFX to Global Library
Go to Preferences (or File -&amp;gt; Settings) -&amp;gt; Appearance &amp;amp; Behavior -&amp;gt;
Path Variables, and define the name of the variable as PATH_TO_FX, and browse to the lib folder of the JavaFX SDK to set its value, and click apply.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Environment Setup</title>
      <link>https://zarif98sjs.github.io/posts/java-environment-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 19:22:10 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zarif98sjs.github.io/posts/java-environment-setup/</guid>
      <description>JDK and JRE Setup JRE not needed for Version &amp;gt; 10
Download Java LTS (Java 8, Java 11, …)
 Oracle JDK 11 Amazon Correto 11 Zulu (includes JavaFX auto in JDK11)  Intellij (&amp;gt;2019.1) comes with bundled JDK which includes JavaFX
Java Path Variable Setup Windows Go to “Advanced System Settings”:
Go to “Environment Variable”
Add New System Variable named “JAVA_HOME” where you have installed your JDK
Edit Path in System Variable and add the location where “javac.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>