<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Java on Md. Jehadul Karim (Sabit)</title>
    <link>https://MJKSabit.github.io/tags/java/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Java on Md. Jehadul Karim (Sabit)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 22:17:02 +0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://MJKSabit.github.io/tags/java/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Share A BIT</title>
      <link>https://MJKSabit.github.io/projects/share-a-bit/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 17:55:52 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://MJKSabit.github.io/projects/share-a-bit/</guid>
      <description>What is Share A BIT Share A BIT is a cross platform file sharing app. It is written in Java with JavaFX. So, if an operating system can run Java (which all major Operating System does), you can use Share A BIT in it.
Moreover, Share A BIT has an Android Client, which makes it way easier to share file to your phone from you pc and vice-verca wirelessly. The Android app can also be used to share files betweeen two android phones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AKash</title>
      <link>https://MJKSabit.github.io/projects/akash/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 22:53:26 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://MJKSabit.github.io/projects/akash/</guid>
      <description>AKash is a simple Banking Application using Java &amp;amp; JavaFX
  Dependencies  JDK 11+ JAVAFX for Java 9+  How to run?  In the release folder, you&amp;rsquo;ll find Jar Files Edit the script files (.bat for windows/.sh for linux) according to your settings Execute the script files (First Server, then Client)  How to use   You can use command line of Server to execute ADMIN works</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Corona Update</title>
      <link>https://MJKSabit.github.io/projects/corona-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 22:17:04 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://MJKSabit.github.io/projects/corona-update/</guid>
      <description>An Android App which shows current situation of corona all over the world.
  It shows,
 Total Number of Infected People Total Number of Recovered People Total number of Active cases Total number of Death  To use the app, you have to be conncted to the Internet.
The app gets data from the Internet.
To avoid unneccesary complexity, I didn&amp;rsquo;t add an other facilities like auto refresh. You can refresh manually by closing and opening the app again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Messenger</title>
      <link>https://MJKSabit.github.io/projects/messenger/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 22:17:04 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://MJKSabit.github.io/projects/messenger/</guid>
      <description>A Simple Multi-Client Messenger with Java Socket Networking&amp;hellip; [ Java Executable Link Given Below ]
  Just like any other messenger, It has
 Sign Up and Log in
Sorting User Depending on Recent Activity
Unread Message Batch
Real time message update (with Customizable Frequency 1Hz)
Black Theme :3
 Screenshots  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Socket Networking</title>
      <link>https://MJKSabit.github.io/posts/java-socket-networking/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 22:17:02 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://MJKSabit.github.io/posts/java-socket-networking/</guid>
      <description>Networking  By Md. Jehadul Karim
 Prerequisite:
 Threading  Recommended:
 Input &amp;amp; Output Stream  So, how do you do Networking. Lets dive into the basics of networking.
Basics of Networking First of all you need to understand how networking is done. There are two types of connection (as far as I know):
 TCP UDP  In this tutorial, I am only going to talk about TCP Networking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Environment Setup</title>
      <link>https://MJKSabit.github.io/posts/java-environment-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 19:22:10 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://MJKSabit.github.io/posts/java-environment-setup/</guid>
      <description>JDK and JRE Setup JRE not needed for Version &amp;gt; 10
Download Java LTS (Java 8, Java 11, …)
 Oracle JDK 11 Amazon Correto 11 Zulu (includes JavaFX auto in JDK11)  Intellij (&amp;gt;2019.1) comes with bundled JDK which includes JavaFX
Java Path Variable Setup Windows Go to “Advanced System Settings”:
Go to “Environment Variable”
Add New System Variable named “JAVA_HOME” where you have installed your JDK
Edit Path in System Variable and add the location where “javac.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>